So you all requested that
I make more comparison videos of insurance companies. I have
made many comparison videos in the past as well, so now you will
see that in the next one month I am
working on videos of many comparison products. There are going to be a
lot of videos in the next one month.
So my
effort there is to compare on maximum parameters
so that your decision
making becomes even wiser. So after
reading the complete IAD report,
I am sharing this simple comparison
with you to find out the relevant things for you, so that you buy the right policy.
So today's comparison is for three policies. The
first is ISI Lombard Complete
Health Insurance. The second is Niva Papa Rea
Share Plan. The third is I am
associated with hdfcergo.com and every week I
bring videos for you so that your
personal financial life can become easy and happy
because the tagline of our company is also '
Creating a Wealth of Happiness'.
Let's move on to the video.  Comparison between
ISC Load Complete Health Insurance Niva
Bupa ReAssure and hdfcergo.com
Ratio is 78. Niva Bupa ReAssure has a claim
settlement ratio of 78, and its incurrence claim ratio
is
96. ADAC Ergo has a claim settlement
ratio of 99.8 and its incurrence claim ratio is 73. We will
talk about cashless hospitals and how
big is their network. This is pan India. So
ICSC Labad has almost
5100 network hospitals across India. Niva Bupa has
8700 network hospitals and ADAC
Ergo has 100000 network hospitals. We will
talk about claim settlement.
How does the claim settlement happen? It happens through TPA,
meaning through a third party administrator
or is it in-house. So, the TPA of all three is
in-house. All three have their own
team of doctors for claims settlement who support you in claim settlement. So, there is
no third party involved.  Which means faster claim
settlement. Sum short options are available
in ICC Lombard. Minimum it is 5 lakhs
and maximum up to 50 lakhs is available. There
are many variants in ICC Load Complete Health Insurance. If you
want to watch all these videos in detail, then
all these videos are available on our channel.
We will put their links in the description box as well.
If you want to refer to them, you
can also refer to the detailed video. So sum short options from 5 lakhs to 50
lakhs are available. You
can choose in NB ReAssure and
hdfc0000082. You will get 3 years option. If we
talk about room rent, then there is
no limit on room rent in all three policies.
You can take any room. If we
talk about day care coverage, there are
150 illnesses listed in NB Lombard
which come under the day care list. There is no list in
NB ReAssure and HDFC Ergo
ReStore.  All day
care procedures are covered. Day care means
that you do not need 24 hours of hospitalization.
You are discharged before 24 hours due
to
advancement of science and technology. So, for
some surgeries like cataract,
earlier you had to be admitted for cataract.
Now you do
not need to be admitted. You go in the morning and come back in the evening
or hardly come back in three to four hours. So,
all day care procedures
are covered here. Domicile hospitalization means
that if you are
not in a condition to go to the hospital or
beds are not available in the hospital, then
domicile hospitalization is covered in all three policies
up to sum assured refill benefit. So, the
refill benefit is unlimited in IIC Lombard, which
means if your
base sum assured gets exhausted, then
in IIC, your base sum assured will be refilled for unlimited number of terms.
But there is a
clause that it can be taken only on unrelated illness.
Unlimited refill benefit is also available in Vava Map Reassure.
You can avail it for anything. There
is no clause here. You can get multiple refills
up to base sum assured. There is no clause whether it is
same illness or unrelated illness or
related illness. You
can avail it for anything. Once a year
refill benefit is available in ADAC Ergo. You can avail it only once in a year. There is
no restriction for anything. You
can avail it for anything. Another new feature has been
added in the new variant of ADAC Restore.
In it, you have the option to
opt for unlimited refill option by
paying extra premium.
Pre and post hospitalization is the
expenses before leaving the hospital and
after returning home from the hospital. So these
expenses should be related to your hospitalization.
ICICI Lombard
reimburses you for 30 days pre hospitalization expenses.  You can get it done and 60 days post
Niva Bupa Reassure and
90 days is the pre and post
hospitalization expenses that you can get
reimbursed No Claim Bonus So No Claim Bonus
if you do not take a claim then the company
gives you a bonus, it gives you an incentive
that is No Claim Bonus your ADAC
you get your No Claim Bonus at 10 every year
maximum it is
50 per annum in Niva Bupa Reassure you get it at 50 every year maximum
it goes up to 100% and in ADAC Orgo
Restore also you will get it at 50 every year
maximum it goes up to 100% modern
treatments so we will talk about modern treatments
as you are seeing nowadays
modern treatments on robotic surgeries are also becoming
popular modern treatments are covered up to some shot in ICS Lord Complete
Health Insurance modern treatments are
covered up to some shot in Niva Bupa Reassure
modern treatments are covered
up to some shot except there is a limit of
₹1 lakh on some robotic surgeries There are some
robotic surgeries in which only ₹1 lakh will be given as of
now There is no limit in ADFC Ergo Optima
Restore as well Covered
up to 500,000 organ donors Talking about organ donors,
organ donor transplant
is covered in all three policies ICACC Lombard has a
limit of ₹10 lakhs.
₹1 lakh will be given for the entire process IB Resh and
hdfcergo.com can add on where as no
such option is available Maternity benefits in Niva Bupa
Resh and ADFC Auro Optima Restore
Talking about maternity benefits, in ISI load you have the
option to add maternity benefits.
They have an elite plan, you can choose that
if you want maternity benefits
Maternity benefits are not available in Niva Bupa Resh and ADFC Auro Optima Restore,
nor is there any option to add
AYUSH treatments  AYUSH is Ayurvedic,
Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy, so
its hospitalization is also there in your policy.
There are registered hospitals for AYUSH,
if there is hospitalization in them then that is also
covered in ICC Lombard, it is covered
in Complete Health Insurance, it is
covered in Nivaup Reassure,
AYUSH is not covered in HDFC ARG Optima Restore.
Now let's talk about Compliance, the
company is focusing on your illness
because it is giving you hospitalization benefit, it
is also focusing on your wellness, it is
also focusing on your health, so
for that you get some complimentary wellness tests done
once a year in ICSC Lombard,
if it is an individual policy then you
get one coupon, if it is a family floater then you
get two coupons, you can get the test done
or you can get it done even after taking the policy,
you do not have to wait in this,
in Nivabu Reassure you can claim Rs 500 per lakh sum
assured,
in individual policy the maximum is Rs 5000
in family floater policy  You can claim ₹ 00 in
ADAC ARG Optima Restore.
In the individual policy,
you can claim wellness benefits of ₹ 5000 in the floater policy. There are
complete tests which you can get done for a full body
checkup. Now let's talk about
wellness benefits. Some
companies also provide you wellness benefits, for example,
ICSA Lombard has an option for HRA
risk assessment.
Here you get points
and you can convert those points
into OPD and use them. So you get
your tests done and do a risk assessment.
Suppose you got a
diagnostic test done and its range is
good, that is, the levels are
good levels and are within this range. If
you want to watch this video for details, then
everything is explained in detail in it.  There are
wellness benefits as well in Ava Bappa Reassure. You can avail this
Live Healthy benefit by
downloading the application and you get a discount based on the number of steps you complete.
Same is for HDFC Reassure Health.
You will get a discount based on the number of steps you complete.
You can track it through your application.
Mobile
applications of all three are available. The
name of the mobile application of IS Loard is Oil Tech
Care. The name of the application of Ava Bappa is Niva
Bappa Health Insurance
hdfcfund.com. The
premium charged for Complete Health Insurance in India is the
same pan India, whether you live in Delhi,
Jaipur, Madhya Pradesh
or Himachal Pradesh,
anywhere. The
premium for Zone 1, Zone 2, Zone 3 is the same.
So, the same premium will be charged. There are
two zones in Niva Bappa Reassure and HDFC Reassure Optima Reassure. Zone 1 is
Delhi NCR, Mumbai and some parts of Gujarat.
You are charged a higher premium there.  Zone
2 has a slightly lower premium. The
concept is the same in both the policies, having said that there is
no co-payment. If
you have been charged the premium of Zone 2 as well, then if
you are getting treatment done in Zone 1 or
anywhere else, then there is
no co-payment of any kind. There is no sub-limit. So, there is
no co-payment in all the three policies. You know the waiting periods. All the
three policies will have an initial waiting period of
30 days. For the first 30 days, you
cannot get planned hospitalization. Only
accidental emergency is covered. Rest, we will talk about
specific exclusions. The
waiting period for slow-growing illnesses is
24 months in all the three policies. The
waiting period for pre-assisting diseases is
24 months in IC Lombard Health Insurance. It is 24 months in Niva Vapa Reassure and
36 months in both ADAC Ago Optima Restore.
Now we will talk about it. We have compared the
different parameters. I hope
I have covered all the points. If you
think  If I have missed something then you
can tell me so that I can
add that in the next comparison video as well. Here now
I would like to tell you about the premium comparison. I would like to see
how much the premium is. I have
taken a family of four here, the age is 45, 40, 17
and 12, so I have taken a family of four and have
taken zone one premium. So on the basis of this
you can see which one
is suitable for you, what features do you want more
in your policy, you know what
thing you give more importance to,
you can choose the policy accordingly. This was the
comparison from my side, ICSC Lombard
Complete Health Insurance, Niva, Bupa, Resurs
and HDSC R Go, Optima Restore. If you have
any questions regarding these plans, please
tell me. Detail videos are also available as
I told you. If you want to give any feedback, please tell me. If you want to
tell me on what should I
make the next video or on
what comparison videos would you like to see, please tell me that too.
I will try.
Quick reminder before leaving to make videos, if right now  If
you have not yet subscribed to our channel, do
subscribe so that you get the right
information at the right time and see you
soon. Stay safe, take care, bye
and